Guide to the Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory records, 1958-2000.
Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory records
- Series V. Publications
  - News Articles
    - Astronomy.com - "Astronomers Hit Pulsar Bulls-Eye" (Kelly Kizer Whitt), 7/3/2002 (Box 54, Folder 302.1)
    - Oberlin online - "Searching the Skies: Students Observe Pulsars at the Arecibo Observatory" (Sue Kropp), 7/11/2002 (Box 54, Folder 303)
    - Astronomy.com - "Close Encounter with an Asteroid" (Elsa Janke), 8/11/2002 (Box 54, Folder 303.1)
    - New York Times - "Missing Spacecraft May Have Broken Apart" (Warren E. Leary), 8/17/2002 (Box 54, Folder 303.2)
    - Astronomy.com - "Lord of the Ring Galaxies" (Richard Talcott), 9/6/2002 (Box 54, Folder 303.3)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Space radio pioneer Harold Ewen to give inaugural Arecibo lecture" (David Brand), 10/24/2002 (Box 54, Folder 304)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "A new Cornell group presides over changes at Arecibo Observatory" (David Brand), 12/12/2002 (Box 54, Folder 305)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Goldsmith steps down after a decade at NAIC" (David Brand), 12/12/2002 (Box 54, Folder 306)
    - Cornell News Release - "Arecibo Observatory undergoing major changes, to be overseen by newly appointed Cornell management committee" (David Brand), 12/20/2002 (Box 54, Folder 307)
    - Sciencenter News - "Bill Gordon Honored on Wall of Inspiration", 2003 (Box 54, Folder 308)
    - Nature - "Shake up for management at Arecibo radio telescope", 1/2/2003 (Box 54, Folder 309)
    - Cornell News Release - "Arecibo director's new book is a witty, colorful exploration of a universe of violent change and mysterious life forms" (Briana Collins '03), 1/16/2003 (Box 54, Folder 310)
    - Cornell Daily Sun - "Committee to Manage Arecibo Observatory" (Erica Temel), 1/22/2003 (Box 54, Folder 311)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Robert L. Brown is named to head NAIC and its Arecibo Observatory" (Briana Collins), 1/23/2003 (Box 54, Folder 312)
    - National Geographic - "Telescopio de Arecibo", Mar-03 (Box 54, Folder 313)
    - UCBerkeley News - "Search for ET to look again at 150 signals" (Robert Sanders), 3/10/03 (Box 54, Folder 313.1)
    - NASA Langley Res. Ctr - "NASA Educational Show to Feature Arecibo Observatory" (Kimberly Land, Jose Acevedo), 3/10/2003 (Box 54, Folder 314)
    - Nature.com - "Alien hunters take a closer look" (John Whitfield), 3/12/2003 (Box 54, Folder 314.1)
    - Space.com - "Smallest Deep Space Structures Detected, Study Claims" (Robert Roy Britt), 3/12/2003 (Box 54, Folder 314.2)
    - United Press Int'l - "Space 'beachballs' generate pulsar bursts" (Lidia Wasowicz), 3/12/2003 (Box 54, Folder 314.3)
    - Newsweek - "E.T., Phone Here" (Jerry Adler), 3/17/2003 (Box 54, Folder 315)
    - NRAO Newsletter - "Robert Brown to Assume NAIC Directorship" (C.E. Blue), Apr 2003 (Box 54, Folder 316)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "NSF awards Arecibo Observatory and University of Puerto Rico $600,000 to train Hispanic students in scientific research" (David Brand), 6-9-03 (Box 54, Folder 317)
    - MSNBC.com - "World's biggest dish opens wider - Scientists give Arecibo Observatory a makeover at 40" (Alan Boyle), 7/28/03 (Box 54, Folder 318)
    - Connecting with Cornell - "Brown Heads NAIC and Arecibo", Fall 2003 (Box 54, Folder 319)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Sixto Gonzalez named first Puerto Rico-born head of Arecibo Observatory" (David Brand), 9/25/03 (Box 54, Folder 320)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo Observatory program takes aim at Hispanic audience by promoting science and education in Puerto Rico" (David Brand), 9/25/03 (Box 54, Folder 321)
    - New York Times - "Saturn's Biggest Moon Starts to Divulge Some of Its Secrets" (Kenneth Chang), 10/07/03 (Box 54, Folder 322)
    - Space Explorers Planetary Times - "Astronomers Find Evidence of Hydrocarbon Lakes on Titan", 10/08/03 (Box 54, Folder 323)
    - Puerto Rico Herald - "Arecibo Observatory to Celebrate 40 Years", 10/08/03 (Box 54, Folder 324)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Asteroid Hermes, lost for 66 years, is found to be two objects orbiting each other, astronomers using Arecibo telescope report" (David Brand), 10/23/03 (Box 54, Folder 325)
    - UCLA News - "Large Asteroid, Lost for 66 Years, Is Found to Be Two Objects Orbiting Each Other" (J.L. Margot), 10/23/03 (Box 54, Folder 326)
    - New York Times - "An Asteroid's Surprise", 10/28/03 (Box 54, Folder 327)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Astronomer Tor Hagfors to give Gordon Lecture at Arecibo Nov. 3" (David Brand), 10/28/03 (Box 54, Folder 328)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Father of Arecibo telescope to give 40th anniversary address" (David Brand), 10/28/03 (Box 54, Folder 329)
    - US House of Reps - One Minute on the 40th Anniversary of the Arecibo Observatory (Anibal Acevedo Vila, Comisionado Residente en Washington), 10/30/03 (Box 54, Folder 330)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Rain fails to dampen emotion and nostalgia of 40th birthday event at Arecibo Observatory" (David Brand & Linda Grace-Kobas), 11/06/03 (Box 54, Folder 331)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo radar shows no evidence of thick ice at lunar poles, despite data from previous spacecraft probes, researchers say" (David Brand), 11-12-03 (Box 54, Folder 332)
    - SETI News - "The fate of the NASA HRMS, soon to be reborn as Project Phoenix" (Jill Tarter), 1st Qtr 1994 (Box 54, Folder 332.1)
    - Connecting with Cornell - "Entrusted with a National Treasure of Transnational Significance, Cornell Orchestrates Celestially at the Arecibo Observatory", Winter 2004 (Box 54, Folder 333)
    - Nature.com - Movers - Sixto Gonzalez, director, Arecibo Observatory, Puerto Rico, 1/15/04 (Box 54, Folder 334)
    - IEEE Antennas & Propgation Magazine - "Arecibo Observatory 40th Anniversary Celebration" (Allan W. Love), Feb 2004 (Box 54, Folder 335)
    - BBC News Online - "Radio search for ET draws a blank" (Dr. David Whitehouse), 3/25/04 (Box 54, Folder 336)
    - "The ALFA Story" (Graeme Carrad), Apr-04 (Box 54, Folder 337)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Discovery of water would make proposed lunar base possible, but recovery will be hard, Cornell astronomer tells House committee" (David Brand), 4/01/04 (Box 54, Folder 338)
    - Newswise.com - "Arecibo Radiotelescope Made Incredibly More Sensitive", 4/21/04 (Box 54, Folder 339)
    - The Economist - "Dark side of the moon", 4/24/04 (Box 54, Folder 340)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo gets a 7-pixel eye on the sky and unprecedented sensitivity" (David Brand), 4/29/04 (Box 54, Folder 341)
    - Univ. Virginia - Astronomy Picture of the Month - pulsar PSR J0528+2200, 5/4/04 (Box 54, Folder 342)
    - Geneseo Emcompass Mag. - "Physics Professor Solving Curious Case of Missing Meteors" (Mary E. McCrank), Winter 2005 (Box 54, Folder 343)
    - Cornell News Release - "Arecibo's sensitive new eye begins massive sky survey--perhaps discovering that starless galaxies exist" (David Brand), 2/3/2005 (Box 54, Folder 344)
    - OE Magazine.com - "Arecibo's sensitive new eye begins massive sky survey", 2/8/2005 (Box 54, Folder 345)
    - El Nuevo Dia - "El latido de una estrella" (Por Iris Monica Vargas), 3/1/2005 (Box 54, Folder 346)
    - Primera Hora - "Inestable el ambiente en el Observatorio) (Wilma Maldonado Arrigoitia), 3/23/2005 (Box 54, Folder 347)
    - The Ithaca Journal - "Cornell observatory contract renewed" (Journal Staff), 4/6/2005 (Box 54, Folder 348)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Washington renews Arecibo contract" (David Brand), 4/7/2005 (Box 54, Folder 349)
    - Cornell Daily Sun - "NSF Renews Arecibo Contract" (David Hillis), 4/8/2005 (Box 54, Folder 350)
    - El Nuevo Dia - "Luciernagas' en el cielo nocturno" (Por Iris Monica Vargas), 4/26/2005 (Box 54, Folder 351)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Summer school brings students, researchers to Arecibo to learn, wonder" (Lauren Gold), 8/18/2005 (Box 54, Folder 352)
    - Physorg.com - Press Release - "New evidence for a Dark Matter Galaxy" (Robert Minchin), 1/12/2006 (Box 54, Folder 353)
    - SpaceRef.com - Press Release - "Discovery of the Youngest Ever Binary Pulsar", 1/13/2006 (Box 54, Folder 354)
    - CU Chronicle Magazine - “How data mining retrieves gold nuggets from a universe of data”, 1/26/2006 (Box 54, Folder 355)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "New Arecibo receiver triggers quiet revolution that could discover thousands of galaxies" (Lauren Gold), 3/9/2006 (Box 54, Folder 356)
    - Travel & Tourism PR - "Eye in the Sky: The Arecibo Observatory" (Ronald C. Flores), Apr-Jun 2006 (Box 54, Folder 357)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Leave the skates on Earth -- Cornell researchers find no evidence of ice reserves on the moon" (Lauren Gold), 10/18/2006 (Box 54, Folder 358)
    - Cornell Daily Sun - "Arecibo May Lose Funding" (Lisa Grossman), 11/9/2006 (Box 54, Folder 359)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Obervations of double asteroid stress Arecibo radar's vital role in identifying threats in Earth's vicinity" (Lauren Gold), 11/15/2006 (Box 54, Folder 360)
    - Cornell Chronicle - Saving Arecibo: Observatory's radar and unique precision make it a vital resource, argues NAIC director" (Lauren Gold), 1/18/2007 (Box 54, Folder 361)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Tor Hagfors, astronomy professor and Arecibo pioneer, dies at age 76" (, 1/24/2007 (Box 54, Folder 362)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Robert B. Kerr named director of Arecibo Observatory", 2/6/2007 (Box 54, Folder 363)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Asteroids spin at YORP speed, thanks to the effects of sunlight, Cornell and Belfast astronomers discover" (Lauren Gold), 3/7/2007 (Box 54, Folder 364)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "CU, NAIC search for funding to keep Arecibo's radar alive" (Melissa Rice), 6/27/2007 (Box 54, Folder 365)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo telescope's global users converge on nation's capital to plan threatened observatory's scientific future", 9/13/2007 (Box 54, Folder 366)
    - Cornell Alumni Magazine - "Sky's the Limit - Arecibo Observatory is the world's most sensitive radio telescope --but NSF funding cuts may put it out of business" (Beth Saulnier), Sep/Oct 2007 (Box 54, Folder 367)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Congress gets bill to save Arecibo Observatory", 10/3/2007 (Box 54, Folder 368)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Campbell, Planetary Society urge Congress to save Arecibo" (Lauren Gold), 11/9/2007 (Box 54, Folder 369)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Freshly painted Arecibo Observatory returns to work, spies object assicated with meteor showers", 12/21/2007 (Box 54, Folder 370)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo telescope finds critical ingredients for the soup of life in a galaxy far, far away", 1/14/2008 (Box 54, Folder 371)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Neutron stars can be more massive, while black holes are more rare, Arecibo Observatory finds", 1/17/2008 (Box 54, Folder 372)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo astronomers prepare for asteroid closeup" (Lauren Gold), 1/25/2008 (Box 54, Folder 373)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo Observatory astronomers discover first near-Earth triple asteroid just 7 million miles away" (Blaine Friedlander), 2/13/2008 (Box 54, Folder 374)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Partnership agreement will bring $23M annually to Arecibo Observatory for outreach, education" (Lauren Gold), 4/16/2008 (Box 54, Folder 375)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Planetary scientist Don Campbell named director of Cornell center that manages NSF's Arecibo Observatory" (Blaine Friedlander), 5/1/2008 (Box 54, Folder 376)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Quirky pulsar system discovered at Arecibo challenges theories of binary formation" (Lauren Gold), 5/15/2008 (Box 54, Folder 377)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo joins global network to create 6,000-mile telescope" (Lauren Gold), 6/6/2008 (Box 54, Folder 378)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Clintons (minus Hillary) visit Arecibo; former president urges more federal funding for basic sciences" (Lauren Gold), 6/5/2008 (Box 54, Folder 379)
    - Cornell Pawprint - "Cornell mourns the loss of George Peter", 8/15/2008 (Box 54, Folder 380)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo pulsar survey is using 50,000 PCs worldwide to generate supercomputing power" (Lauren Gold), 3/25/2009 (Box 54, Folder 381)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Report calls Arecibo Observatory 'uniquely powerful' for detecting near-Earth objects" (Anne Ju), 9/29/2009 (Box 54, Folder 382)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Report: Arecibo unparalleled for finding near-Earth objects" (Lauren Gold), 1/26/2010 (Box 54, Folder 383)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Bill Gordon, father of Arecibo Observatory, dies at 92" (Lauren Gold, 2/18/2010 (Box 54, Folder 384)
    - New York Times - "W.E. Gordon, Creator of Link to Deep Space, Dies at 92" (Douglas Martin), 2/28/2010 (Box 54, Folder 385)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Friends of celebrate life of astronomer Bill Gordon" (Lauren Gold), 4/14/2010 (Box 54, Folder 386)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo telescope track 'potentially dangerous' asteroid within 1.5 million miles of Earth" (Blaine Friedlander), 4/30/2010 (Box 54, Folder 387)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Home computers from Iowa and Germany, using Arecibo data, help discover unusual pulsar" (Lauren Gold), 8/12/2010 (Box 54, Folder 388)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "National report makes for 'a good day' for CU astronomy" (Anne Ju), 8/18/2010 (Box 54, Folder 389)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "SRI International to manage Arecibo Observatory", 6/3/2011 (Box 54, Folder 390)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Civil engineer William McGuire dies at age 92", 2/12/2013 (Box 54, Folder 391)
- Series VI. Reports
  - Research Reports, 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Construction Design Reports, 1960-1963 (Box 1)
  - Five Year Plan Report, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Report on Reflector, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Reports on Arecibo Transmitter, 1972 (Box 1)
  - NAIC Progress Reports, 1990-2006 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - NAIC Progress Reports, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - NAIC Progress Reports, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - NAIC Progress Report, 2003 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - NAIC Progress Report, 2004-2005 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - NAIC Progress Report, 2006-2010 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Advisory Committee Reports, 1970-1978 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Advisory Committee Reports, 1972-1977 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Advisory Committee Reports, 1978-1980 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Advisory Committee Reports, 1981-1987 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Advisory Committee Reports, 1985-1994 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Advisory Committee Reports, 1988-1992 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Advisory Committee Reports, 1995-2010 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Visiting Committee Reports, 1993-2002 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Visiting Committee Reports, 2003-2010 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Computer Department Reports 1-6, 1976-1982 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Computer Department Reports 7-12, 19771980 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Computer Department Reports 13-22, 1980-1982 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Arecibo Final Report, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Measurement of the Structural Response of a New Ring-Girder Hanger at the Arecibo Observatory - Final Report, 1993 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Arecibo Hairin Testing, 1997 (Box 25, Folder 3-4)
  - Structural Condition Survey, 2003 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Arecibo Diagrams - Repair, 2010 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Questions and Suggestions for Studies and Action Concerning Arecibo - From Bill McGuire, November 2010 (Box 25, Folder 7)
- Series VII. Memorabilia
  - t-shirts, miscellaneous (Box 13)
  - Posters
    - Nov 1 1963 Dedication, NY Times (Box 64)
    - Aerial of Arecibo Observatory, by Dale Corson, 1978 (Box 64)
    - Inauguration of Arecibo Observatory, 1997 (Box 64)
    - Visit by Bill & Chelsea Clinton, May 2008 (Box 64)
    - William E Gordon, Father of the Arecibo Observatory (in memoriam), 2010 (Box 64)
    - 1 Poster combining: 12m Antenna, Ionospheric Interaction Facility, Power Generators, Expansion of Angel Ramos Foundation Visitor Center, 2011 (Box 64)
    - 40th Anniversary, 2003 (Box 64)
    - 20 Decades of Pulsar Science: The Fab Five Fest, March 20-22, 2011 (Box 64)